Guide to the John Judson Trappan Photographs 1888–1912, undated PR 071
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Negatives, 1890–1903, undated
  - Subseries II.B. Glass Plate Negatives (4 x 5"), 1890–1901, undated
    - Glass Plate Negatives (4 x 5")—numbered [part 3 of 5], 1895–1896 (Box 8)
      287—Old Centre Church, 1895 July-August
      288—Judge's Cave, 1895 July-August
      289—Downtown buildings, NY, 1895 April
      291—Inter Yacht Race pictures, 1895 September
      292—Inter Yacht Race pictures, 1895 September
      293—Inter Yacht Race pictures, 1895 September
      298—Dr. Tredwell's Office, 1896 May 1
      300—He & She (A. Gardener Cooper & Miss Cooper), 1896 May 9
      301—at Flatlands—#1 Cycle Camera, 1896 May 9
      302—Engine, 1896 May 30
      303—Cavalry, 1896 May 30
      304—Cavalry scratched, 1896 May 30
      306—Seymour Corll's house, group, 1896 May 30
      307—Seymour Corll's house, group, 1896 May 30
      308—Our backyard, willow, 1896 June
      309—Reflections – Prospect Park, 1896 June 18
      311—Sheep & Shepherd, Prospect park, 1896 June 18
      312—"Room for more"—B.B.B., 1896 June 18
      313—Cooper's Sail—boys on deck, 1896 June 13
      314—Cooper's Sail—boys on stern, 1896 June 13
      315—Brenda, 1896 July 4
      316—Sue with wheel on piazza, 1896 July 4
    - Glass Plate Negatives (4 x 5")—numbered [part 4 of 5], 1896–1897 (Box 9)
      317—Sue with wheel on lawn, 1896 July 4
      318—The "Susye," bow on, 1896 July 4
      319—The "Susye," 1896 July 4
      320—Cows & calf, Binghamton, 1896 July 23
      321—Cows, 1896 July 23
      322—Ed & Katie with rake, 1896 July 23
      323—Ed & chickens, 1896 July 23
      324—Chickens at door, 1896 July 23
      326—Load of hay, 1896 July 23
      330—Ella with wheel at Branford Point, 1896 September
      331—Ella on wheel near Branford Point, 1896 September
      332—Cottage, 1896 September
      333—Ella & calf, 1896 September
      334—Shore front—Pequot house, 1896 September
      335—Shore front, 1896 September
      336—Shore front—McCleve house, 1896 September
      337—Shore front—Beechers, 1896 September
      338—Shore front at Branford, 1896 September
      339—New England Dinner—Girls #1, 1896 November
      340—New England Dinner—Girls #2, 1896 November
      341—Armenian booth, 1896 November
      343—Men, 1896 November
      344—Roadway, Prospect Park, 1896 December 25
      345—View of Lake, Prospect Park, 1896 December 25
      346—Sleighing scene, Prospect Park, 1896 December 25
      349 —Broadway & Maiden lane, McKinley Decemberorations, 1896 October
      351—Anniversary—Throop Ave. pier, 1897 May
      352—Anniversary, 1897 May
      353—Anniversary, 1897 May
      354—Anniversary, 1897 May
      355—Cycling, Bensonhurst, Church, 1897 June
      361—Grant Day, Tomb, 1897 April
      362—Grant Day, Tomb, 1897 April
      363—Grant Day, Ships, 1897 April
      364—Grant Day, SS "New York," 1897 April
      366—Grant Day, Temporary Arch, 1897 April
      369—Ex Com, building fire, 1897 June
      370—Ex Com, in the Adelaide, 1897 June
      371—Boys at Coney Island, 1897 June
      374—Sue & others on dock, 1897 July
      375—E.J.O. & fish, 1897 July
      376—Will Rowland's horse "Nomad," 1897 July
      377—Will Rowland's horse "Nomad," 1897 July
      378—Sue at Morris Cove, 1897 July
      379—Sue at Morris Cove, 1897 July
      380—Minot girls, 1897 July
      381—Minot girls at bath house, 1897 July
      382—Cottage at cove, 1897 August
      383—Cottage at cove, 1897 August
      384—Washington trip, Congressional Library, 1897 July
      385—Washington trip, Congressional Library, 1897 July
      386—Shoes, 1897 July
      387—White House, people, 1897 July
      388—White House, people, 1897 July
      389—E.L.T. & wheel, 1897 July
      391—Viewdelieu, Hollyoak, Delaware, 1897 July
    - Glass Plate Negatives (4 x 5")—numbered [part 5 of 5], 1897–1901 (Box 10)
      392—Mt. Vernon, 1897 July
      393—Capitol, 1897 July
      394—Tomb of Washington, 1897 July
      395—Wanamaker's, 1897 July
      396—Independence Hall, 1897 July
      398—Wash. Monument at Trenton, 1897 July
      400—Bayside, Perth Amboy, 1897 July
      401—Toll Gate, 1897 July
      402—J.J.T.—making repairs, 1897 July
      403—Tompkins Ave. Church, Thanksgiving Day, 1897 November
      404—Eagle Rock trip, Miss Darrow, 1898 February-March
      406—Gateway, 1898 February-March
      408—Rounding Battery, 1898 February-March
      410—Group at lunch, 1898 February-March
      411—"Paris" Day, 1898 May
      412—"World" War Bulletin, 1898 May
      414—Manhattan Co. Tank on Centre St., 1898 May
      416—Elsie Brown, profile, Passaic, 1898 August
      417—Elsie Brown, front, 1898 August
      418—Belle Cadman at Cove, 1898 August
      419—Park Chapel, 1898 August
      420—Beecher's Bro-house, 1898 August
      421—Beecher's from water, 1898 August
      422—Group at Fort Hamilton watching returning of fleet, 1898 August
      426—2 schooners, 1898 August
      428—Farewell party to Hadley Ford at Comstock, 1898 August
      429—Bridge at cove, 1898 August
      430—Rob McCleve's new house, 1898 August
      431—School classroom, 1898 August
      432—Street's house, 1898 August
      433—Brook & hay mounds near No. Winstown (?), 1898 October
      435—Guns at South East fort, 1898 August
      437—Converted yacht "Freelance," 1898 August
      438—Watkins boy & dog, 1898 August
      439—Girls on stone wall, 1898 August
      440—Park chapel #2, 1898 August
      441—The cliff, 1898 August
      443—Columbia Col. Library, 1899 February 22
      445—Bronx Dam, 1899 February 22
      446—Houses on 82nd Street, 1899 September
      454—Scene in Detroit, C.E. crowd, 1899 July 4
      455—Scene in Detroit, Light tower & Majestic bldg., 1899 July 4
      456—Scene in Detroit, lunch tents, 1899 July 4
      457—Scene in Detroit, small tents, 1899 July 4
      458—Scene in Detroit, 1st Cong. Church, Dr. Boynton's, 1899 July 4
      461—Bennett house, front stoop, 1899 July 4
      462—Bennett house, rear, 1899 July 4
      466—Bennett house, porch, 1899 July 4
      467—Dewey Day, crowd on B'way & Bond St., 1899 September
      472—No. Wash. Square house, 1899 September
      474—Fire in South St., 1899 March
      475—Fire in South St., 1899 March
      476—Grant's Tomb, 1899 February 22
      477—Foliage near Flushing, 1899 October
      478—Corn stacks, Flushing to Jamaica, 1899 October
      479—Road near Flushing, 1899 October
      487—Scene in Prospect Park, 1900 September
      489—Laying corner stone, 1901 January 1
      494—
    - Glass Plate Negatives (4 x 5")—unnumbered, 1896, 1899, undated (Box 11)
      Bennett House, Michigan (3), 1896
      Dewey Days (1), 1899
      McKinley Decorations (5), 1896
      Outdoor Views, undated
      Animals (3), undated
      Cannons (1), undated
      Groups (4), undated
      Prospect Park (1), undated
      Residences (3), undated
      Rooftops (1), undated
      Street Scenes (3), undated
      Water Scenes (5), undated
  - Subseries II.C. Glass Plate Negatives (5 x 8"), 1890–1896, undated
    Numbered glass plate negatives are housed sequentially from 012 to 216; there are gaps in the series. The negatives correspond to the entries in the photographer's logbook (Subseries II.A). Unnumbered negatives follow the numbered negatives, and have been arranged by subject. The quantity of negatives in each subject grouping is listed in parentheses.
    - Glass Plate Negatives (5 x 8")—numbered, 1890–1894 (Box 12)
      012—Rustic House and Bridge, Prospect Park, 1890 February 22
      015—Group & snow ball, Prospect Park, 1890 March 20
      017—Elevated RR & backyard, 210 Stockton, 1890 April 1
      027b—
      028—Group 13 teachers, PS #53, 1890 May 9
      029—Group 11 teachers, PS #53, 1890 May 9
      039—Governor's Island from Produce Exchange tower, 1890 June 19
      042—Cottage, Morris Cove, 1890 July 14
      043—Bathing scene, Morris Cove, 1890 July 15
      047—Pavilion of McCleve House, Morris Cove, 1890 July 18
      083a—Group, Spring Valley, 1890 September 7
      085b—Daisy fishing, Spring Valley, 1890 September 7
      086—Allie's House, Spring Valley, 1890 September 7
      087—In the woods, muddy brook, Nanuet, 1890 September 4
      096—Culvert rows, Rockland County, 1892 August 23
      097—Northern RR track, Rockland County, 1892 August 23
      098—Brook & bridge, Allie on right, 1892 August 27
      099—Bridge & brook, Rockland County, Allie in center, 1892 August 27
      101—Flowers—old & young, group, Rockland County, 1892 August 27
      209—Ella & Herbie Sayman, Shady Glen, Catskills, 1894 August
      210—Sayman's sheep, Shady Glen, Catskills, 1894 August
      213—Group at falls, in glen, Shady Glen, Catskills, 1894 August
      214—View from Piazza, Shady Glen, Catskills, 1894 August
      216—Depth of Glen, Shady Glen, Catskills, 1894 August
    - Glass Plate Negatives (5 x 8")—unnumbered, 1890–1896, undated (Box 12)
      Bruce & Cook Co. (3), undated
      Morris Cove, Connecticut (1), 1890
      "My Room" (5 x 7"), undated
      New York State—Brooklyn (2), 1890, 1896
      New York State—Shady Glen, Catskills (3), 1894
      Outdoor Views (1), undated
  - Subseries II.D. Nitrate Film Negatives, 1898–1903, undated
    Negatives are arranged alphabetically by travel destinations. The quantity of negatives in each grouping is listed in parentheses after the subject description.
    Restricted
    Due to the possible combustibility of the nitrate negatives in Subseries II.D, they are kept in cold storage. Before requesting items from Box 13, discuss the possibility of viewing this material with a staff member, keeping in mind that it requires at least two full days to thaw.
    - Nitrate Film Negatives, 1898–1903, undated (Box 13)
      Atlantic City, N.J. (8), undated
      Berkshire Hills, Mass. (10), 1898
      Boston, Mass. (50), 1900
      Buffalo, N.Y. (60), 1901
      Quonocontaug, R.I. (2), undated
      Washington, D.C. (14), 1903
      Unidentified (152), undated
- Series III. Ephemera, 1888–1912, undated
  - Bicycling ephemera, 1897–1901 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 35)
  - Photographic ephemera, 1888, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 36)
  - Pamphlets, 1899–1900 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 37)
  - Travel souvenirs, 1893–1900 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 38)
  - Bruce & Cook material—Print matter, 1912, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 39)
  - Bruce & Cook material—Photographs, 1912, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 40)
  - Hand-painted portfolio and book cover, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 41)